Kobato. 22 TL
“…Day of Farewell.”
Closing Notice
We apologize for the inconvenience, but this preschool has been closed. We humbly apologize. If you have any questions or concerns, please contact the principal, Okiura Sayaka.
Yomogi Preschool’s principal, Okiura Sayaka
Carry-out Nabe
Draft Beer
Pedestrians and Bikes Only
16 eyecatch}
“…Kobato’s Wish.”
Kobato.
What’s making you smile in your sleep?
Was I smiling?
You were smiling ear-to-ear for all the world to see.
Did you have a really nice dream or something?
Y-Yes!
A long time ago…
Huh?
Um…
It was a really happy dream.
Was it a dream about the place you want to go to?
Good morning!
Good morning, Kobato-chan!
What should I help with today?
I’ll be going now.
Yeah. Good work.
Isn’t it a lot to work with?
I’m fine! I’ll keep working!
That’s right.
We’ll have to throw them out if we are going to begin anew.
Throw them out, eh…
Let’s bring these over to the entranceway.
Yes!
Once we’re done with this, let’s have some tea.
It’s a little hard without Fujimoto-kun.
Fujimoto-san’s busy with work, right?
Thank you.
You don’t have to work here if
you have too much on your hands.
No, let me work.
You don’t have to keep saving up now, right?
If you want to fire me, just say so.
No, that’s not it!
You don’t get it…
Sorry…
…about deciding to shut down the preschool.
But I just want you to know this.
I think this is for the best now.
I don’t have any regrets, since Okiura didn’t have to do it.
In the end, I made the decision myself.
That’s how I think of it.
Yes…
What is it?
Um, would you come to the preschool for a bit?
Some of your stuff is still…
There isn’t any.
I don’t care if you throw it all away.
But…
I’m busy, so I won’t go.
It’s Fujimoto.
Sorry, but I’ll be about an hour late.
Fujimoto-san?
Watch it!
Huh? I heard you were going to be late today.
I finished early.
What kind of meek face is that?
You’re making me all sad and gloomy, too.
Sorry.
What’re you thinking about?
What do you want to do?
I don’t know.
But…
But?
It hurts here.
Now that the preschool is closed…
But Sayaka-sensei said it was for the best.
Yet…
Fujimoto, eh?
Huh?
Fujimoto-san?
What’s with that reaction?
You haven’t realized it yet?
Yeesh, for crying out loud.
Kiyokazu-kun?
Good morning.
Are you working today, too?
Yes.
But today’s the day they’re taking down the preschool building-
I’m off.
You could at least take a break today…
Now then.
The neighbor’s left, so I’ll be off too.
You’re going out?
Yeah, I’ll be back tonight.
Don’t make that face!
Okay.
Come on.
You better get going too. You’ll be late.
Yes.
All right, all right, all right…
Stop!
Good work.
Sensei, did you pack up everything?
We brought it all out yesterday.
Then we can get to work right away.
What about that mean-looking guy?
He’s working.
What? What an anti-social.
He’s so cold, despite this place taking care of him.
He’s not cold!
Fujimoto-san is… busy!
R-Right…
Sorry.
Okiura-san asked me to give my regards.
Since he won’t be able to come for a while.
Yes, I heard.
There’s a lot to handle with the higher-ups.
It’s all stuff none of us in the
lower ends would know though.
Th-Then is Okiura-san…
Don’t worry. It’ll work out.
It’s Okiura-san, after all.
Sayaka-sensei!
Kobato-chan!
It’s you!
What’s wrong?
Um… today is goodbye…
So we came to visit.
I told my mom I was coming.
I see.
Thank you.
Boss, can I start?
Sensei, can we start?
Please.
Come on now. It’s dangerous, so let’s stay back.
Okay…
Yeah, do it!
Bye bye.
I’ll tell you again.
That one’s impossible to convince.
Give it up.
Genko-sama, that’s unfair!
You all started having snacks without me.
Time to eat!
Zuishou, shut it.
You’re going to catch Ushagi-san?!
That's right. I’ll take Ushagi-san
hostage and talk it over with him.
Do you really think God will be willing to trade?
It’s better than doing nothing.
Even if we do understand your reasons, it’s not a contract to be taken lightly.
Ginsei’s right.
You seem to be a lot more fired up than you used to.
We can discuss semantics later!
Get a grip!
Didn’t you learn anything from last time?
Hey, you two!
Do you want to try forcing it again?
If you don’t know who’s hurting from this, I’ll show you!
Sorry.
God probably wanted you to learn how to wait.
Well, that certainly is something I’m bad at doing.
Hey!
I know. I won’t do anything.
I am Iorogi.
The one who will be with you from now on.
Sensei, once we finish cleaning up, there’ll be no trespassing here.
Okay.
Thanks for the work.
Yeah. Sensei, you guys take care, too.
See you.
I thought it was a pretty vast place, but now that I see it like this…
Right?
Kobato-chan, I’ve got a favor to ask.
Can I?
Yes.
Help out Fujimoto-kun.
The preschool might have been holding him back.
That’s what I think.
Holding him back? How?
By making Fujimoto-kun remain “hard-working Fujimoto-kun.”
I was relying on Fujimoto-kun.
I should have noticed it earlier.
Thanks for the help, Fujimoto-kun.
Kiyokazu-sensei, play the organ!
I should have told him to work towards what he wanted to do for himself.
No! But Fujimoto-san was really doing his best to…
Yes. All the more reason to.
Because he works too hard…
That’s why, Kobato-chan…
Take care of Fujimoto-kun.
Stay by his side.
What about you, Sayaka-sensei?
That’s not for me to do.
Not anymore.
Kobato-san!
I’m home!
Bad news!
Doumoto, you…
As promised, I didn’t contact the people at Yomogi Preschool.
But I did call your landlady.
Sorry, Kobato-chan.
I didn’t want to worry you.
Worrying about him would-
Um… your arm…
Th-Thank goodness that your injuries weren’t severe…
Don’t push yourself so much!
You’ll worry everyone.
It must be inconvenient when you can’t use your arm, right?
Please tell me if there’s anything I can help with!
I told you the first time we met at Yomogi Preschool.
Stop being so sympathetic and curious.
If you pity me, stop it.
That’s not-
It’s annoying!
That’s not it, Fujimoto-sa…
That’s not it…
For me?
It’s telling you to finish gathering confetti by the next full moon.
If you don’t, it means you accept your fate in accordance with the contract.
Ushagi-san!
How can we extend that deadline?
What’ll happen now?
What should we do now?
Who knows. It’s up to them.
Although I feel some sense of responsibility for this.
If it weren’t for that battle, that girl wouldn’t have…
…gotten hit by accident, and have to go through all this, huh?
I’ll do anything I can!
Just give us another four seasons…
No, one is enough!
Please!
You won’t?!
Hey!